In a world where your product,
brand and service are the same as everyone
else's, it's only your sales process
that differentiates you.
The Challenger sales model.
There's a concept in business
called the North Star Metric.
The North Star metric is the calculation
that drives the company.
In the case of Facebook, their North Star
metric was daily return, average use.
They wanted to optimize for people
returning every day
and using the platform on their way
to monetizing the app.
If you bring the people,
the advertisers will come.
The North Star
metric is a way of framing things.
When you frame something, you cut out
the parts of the image you don't want.
Same thing in business.
Arguments are won and lost based
how people define success or frame
the conversation.
So when you're talking in an interview
or in a sales situation,
you want to use the spin methodology
to rank order
a client's problems in terms of cost
saved and impact generated.
Once you've done that, you can determine
the most important metric achieved today
by the need to framing the conversation
in terms of a metric or measurement
that you can directly influence,
which addresses a problem worth solving
that generates costs, savings and earnings
impact.
You'll give yourself
the highest chance of probability.